MEREDITH STRICKLAND

Fullstack Web Developer | 504.352.8366 | mere.strickland@gmail.com

o LINKS o

Github LinkedIn Technical Project Demos Portfolio Website

o SKILLS o

JavaScript React Ruby on Rails

> Node.js HTML

> > CSS

Python

Adobe Illustrator Adobe Photoshop AutoCAD

PROFILE

Fullstack Web Developer with a passion for making people's lives easier through technology. With experience in JavaScript, React, Node, Ruby on Rails, and a background in Architecture, I bring strong skills in collaboration, adaptability, and client relations. As a gay woman, I see the importance of inclusivity in the development of the tools and technologies that we all use. I truly believe that tech should be by everyone, for everyone.

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

Rita - Slideshow | Demo

Prototype for an app that helps caregivers communicate with each other and keep track of appointments, medications, and daily to-dos

- Collaborated with team to design and build a prototype
- Managed the team from conception to presentation
- Winner of the "People's Choice Award" at LYLAS Labs: Women at Work Hackathon

Trip List - GitHub | Demo

A website where users can add recommendations of things to do in a certain location, search for others recommendations, and add/manage trips to take and ideas for what to do there.

- Designed and built front-end using React, Redux, HTML, CSS, and Semantic UI React
- Utilized JSON web tokens and local storage to store encrypted user information
- · Designed and built back-end using Ruby on Rails

Blobbers - GitHub | Demo

An interactive JavaScript SPA where users gain points by grabbing pieces of the sun, or lose points by running into the falling rain

- Utilized P5.js to create user "sprites" and visual elements
- · Used vanilla JavaScript for all user functionality

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Trustforte Corporation, Writer

November 2017 - present, New York, NY

- Analyze documentation to write 15 educational and professional experience evaluations per week of clients' qualifications for IT positions
- Edit and write technical documents in support of candidates applying for U.S. H-1B visas

Andrew Franz Architect, Designer and Office Manager

January 2016 - March 2017 and Summer 2018, New York, NY

- Collaborated with Associates and Project Managers on design schemes, material specifications, and drawings
- Designed graphics for the company website
- Coordinated designer meetings, arranged interior design orders, provided customer service to incoming clients

Christoff:Finio Architect, Designer

January 2013 - May 2015, New York, NY

- Served as a project manager, scheduling approvals and deadlines between consultants, contractors, and fabricators
- Supervised 10 construction and millwork installations, including carpeting, shelving and cabinetry, and plumbing
- Collaborated with principals researching the most appropriate design schemes for 5 different projects simultaneously
- Surveyed project sites and created floor plans in AutoCad

EDUCATION

Flatiron School, Full Stack Web Development

December 2018 - June 2019, Brooklyn, NY

Bennington College, Visual Arts

Class of 2011, Bennington, VT